The Multiverse unleashed.
Spider-Man: No Way Home is a action, adventure,
science fiction film directed by Jon Watts.
Peter Parker is unmasked and no longer able to separate his normal
life from the high-stakes of being a super-hero.
When he asks for help from Doctor Strange the stakes become even more dangerous,
forcing him to discover what it truly means to be Spider-Man.
Peter Parker / Spider-Man, played by Tom Holland.
MJ, played by Zendaya.
Doctor Strange, played by Benedict Cumberbatch.
Ned Leeds, played by Jacob Batalon.
Happy Hogan, played by Jon Favreau.
Max Dillon / Electro, played by Jamie Foxx.
Spider-Man: No Way Home is a 2021 American superhero film based on the Marvel Comics character Spider-Man,
co-produced by Columbia Pictures and Marvel Studios, and distributed by Sony Pictures Releasing.
It is the sequel to Spider-Man: Homecoming (2017) and Spider-Man: Far From Home
(2019), and the 27th film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
The film was directed by Jon Watts and written by
Chris McKenna and Erik Sommers.
It stars Tom Holland as Peter Parker / Spider-Man alongside Zendaya, Benedict Cumberbatch, Jacob Batalon, Jon Favreau, Jamie
Foxx, Willem Dafoe, Alfred Molina, Benedict Wong, Tony Revolori, Marisa Tomei, Andrew Garfield, and Tobey Maguire.
In the film, Peter asks Dr.
Stephen Strange (Cumberbatch) to use magic to make his identity as Spider-Man a secret
again after it was revealed to the world at the end of Far From Home.
When the spell goes wrong because of Peter's actions, the multiverse is broken open and
several visitors from alternate realities are brought into Peter's universe.
A third MCU Spider-Man film was planned during the
production of Homecoming in 2017.
Negotiations between Sony and Marvel Studios to alter their deal—in which they produce the Spider-Man films together—ended with Marvel
Studios leaving the project in August 2019, but a negative fan reaction led to a new deal between the companies a month later.
Watts, McKenna, Sommers, and Holland were set to return, and filming took place
from October 2020 to March 2021 in New York City and Atlanta.
No Way Home serves as a crossover between the MCU and the previous
Spider-Man films directed by Sam Raimi and Marc Webb.
Several actors reprise their roles from those films, including
previous Spider-Man actors Maguire and Garfield.
The pair's involvement was the subject of wide speculation and numerous leaks despite Sony,
Marvel, and the cast's efforts to conceal their involvement until the film's release.
Spider-Man: No Way Home premiered at the Fox Village Theater in Westwood, Los Angeles, on December 13, 2021, and
was theatrically released in the United States on December 17, as part of Phase Four of the MCU.
The film received positive reviews from critics and grossed $1.921 billion worldwide,
surpassing its predecessor as the highest-grossing film released by Sony Pictures.
It became the highest-grossing film of 2021, the sixth-highest-grossing film at the time of its release, the highest-grossing
Spider-Man film, and set several other box office records, including those for films released during the COVID-19 pandemic.
The film received a nomination for Best Visual Effects at the 94th
Academy Awards, among numerous other accolades.
An extended version of the film, subtitled The More Fun Stuff
Version, had a global theatrical release in September 2022.
An additional film trilogy with Holland is planned, beginning with Spider-Man:
Brand New Day, which is scheduled for release in July 2026.
The film explores themes of new york city, hero,
showdown, magic, loss of loved one.
The tone is thought_provoking.